Finding aid for the Kasai Family papers, 1904-1972 LSC.2010.33
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kasai Family papers
1904-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kasai, Henry Yoshihiko
LSC.2010.33
4 Linear Feet (1 flat box)
The collection consists of the personal and business records of Henry Yoshihiko Kasai. Included are documents and records from Mr. Kasai's involvement in community and civil organizations in Utah and records regarding his internment during World War II. Also among the material are business records of the Kasai Insurance Agency.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332423606533
Biography
Yoshihiko ("Henry") Kasai was born September 25, 1890 at Kawaguchi-mura, Minamitsuru-gun, Tamanashi-ken, Japan to Kisaku Kasai (father ) and Mura Kasai (mother).
In May 1904, Mr. Kasai left Japan in order to attend school in the United States. He arrived in San Francisco on June 8, 1904 aboard the "Kaptic-Maru." He began his elementary school education in Mountain View, California, but joined his father and uncle in September 1906 in Idaho, where they were engaged in farming sugar beets. He attended Idaho Falls High School and graduated in 1913.
In 1915, Mr. Kasai became a life insurance agent for the New York Life Insurance Company covering the states of Idaho and Utah and worked on providing insurance for the local Japanese communities. By 1916 Mr. Kasai was a successful agent living in Utah and was becoming integrally involved in the Salt Lake City community.
In 1937 Mr. Kasai married his wife, Alice, with whom he had six children. Mrs. Kasai was born in Seattle, Washington, but re-entered the United States in 1922 as a Kibei (Japanese Americans born in the U.S. who returned to America after being educated in Japan) from Saga Ken Miyake-Gun, Minobara-Mura.
During World War II, Mr. Kasai was interned for two years, first in Missoula, Montana, then in Fort Sill, Oklahoma, next in Camp Livingston, Louisiana, and, finally, in Santa Fe, New Mexico.
By 1945 he had returned to Salt Lake City, Utah and had resumed his leadership role in community activities, particularly as an emissary between the American and Japanese cultures. In 1954, Mr. Kasai became an American citizen.
Scope and Content
The collection documents the activities of Henry Yoshihiko Kasai and, to a lesser extent, his wife. Alice Kasai. Included are documents and records related to Mr. Kasai's personal and business affairs. Among the material are correspondence, photographs, printed material, newspaper clippings, articles, and business records. Of particular interest are documents related to Mr. Kasai's immigration to the United States and his internment during World War II.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Baseball clubs, 1935-1964, subseries A-C by club
Cultural Exchange, 1950-1965
Japanese American Citizens League, 1933-1964
Japanese Association of Utah, 1926-1940
Salt Lake City Nisei Victory Committee, 1943-1947
Sino-Japanese Relations, 1929-1943
Yoshiko Kasai, 1904-1972, subseries A-B.
Related Material
Manzanar War Relocation Center Records (Collection 122). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.
Japanese American Research Project Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.
Japanese American families -- -Utah -- -Salt Lake City -- -Archival resources; Insurance agents -- -Utah -- -Salt Lake City; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Japanese American Research Project (University of California, Los Angeles); Kasai, Alice--Archives; Kasai, Alice; Kasai, Henry Yoshihiko--Archives
- Baseball clubs
  - Gardena Dragons
    - Correspondence--between Yoshihiko Kasai and George Matsumura, 1964 February 20-June 27 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence--between Yoshihiko Kasai and George Matsumura, 1964 July 1-August 4 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous letters regarding visit to Utah, 1964 May 7-August 18 (Box 104, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents note
      One letter contains biographical information on Yoshihito "Henry" Kasai.
    - Fundraising documents, 1964 July (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Itinerary and schedules for Utah trip, 1964 July-August (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1964 June 21-August 5 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Notes, ca. 1964 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, ca. 1964 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Photographs with team members profiles, ca. 1964 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Printed material--"Easy Does It!", ca. 1964 (Box 104, Folder 10)
      Inspirational article.
    - Program--Gardena Dragons vs. Salt Lake Amateur Baseball All Stars, 1964 August 9 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Sponsorship notes--FOR Club, ca. 1964 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Tournament programs, 1963 August 31-September 2; 1964 August 9 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Travel notes, ca. 1964 July (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Little Tokyo Giants
    - Photographs and roster of team, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 15)
      Includes photos of individual team members and players with family members.
  - Tokyo Giants
    - Correspondence--Between Webster K. Nolan and Henry Kasai, 1935 March 19-1936 April 16 (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence--regarding team visit to Salt Lake City, 1935 March 6-1935 May 28 (Box 104, Folder 17)
      Material in English and Japanese.
    - Miscellaneous material--visit to Salt Lake City, 1935-1936 (Box 104, Folder 18)
      Includes receipts.
    - Newspaper clippings--visit to Salt Lake City, 1935 March (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper clippings--visit to Salt Lake City, 1935 April (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper clippings--visit to Salt Lake City, 1935 May (Box 104, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper clippings--visit to Salt Lake City, 1935 June (Box 104, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper clippings--visit to Salt Lake City, ca. 1934-1936 (Box 104, Folder 23)
    - Photographs--visit to Salt Lake City, 1936 April 26 (Box 104, Folder 24)
      Includes photos of the team members and a photograph of a ball.
    - Press releases regarding U.S. tour, ca. 1935-1936 (Box 104, Folder 25)
    - Radio scripts, 1935 May 27; 1935 May 29 (Box 104, Folder 26)
      Addresses over KSL.
    - Schedule of U.S. games, 1936 February-May (Box 104, Folder 27)
    - Team member list, ca. 1935 - 1936 (Box 104, Folder 28)
    - Tokyo Kyojingun Senshu Keireki [team member background of the Tokyo Giants], 1935 September (Box 104, Folder 29)
      In Japanese.
- Cultural Exchange
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and clippings, 1950 March 3-December 18 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Regarding Cherry Tree drive.
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and clippings, 1951 October 13-December 27 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    Regarding sending Boy Scout equipment to Japan.
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and clippings, 1952 January 3-December 7 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and clippings, 1964 June 2-August 13 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    Material in Japanese and English.
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and printed material, 1951 March 11-July 12 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Boy Scouts--correspondence and printed material, 1953 June 24-July 16 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Chief Abbott Chisan Koho visit to Salt Lake City--correspondence, 1960 November 8-17 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Cultural exchange events (various)--correspondence and clippings, 1954 May 4-1964 July 27 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Friends of the World--correspondence and clippings, 1954 March 9-1955 May 3 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    Regarding Cherry tree seeds.
  - Sister-city program with Matsumoto city, Nagano prefecture--correspondence, 1959 September 4-October 15 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Sister-city program with Matsumoto city, Nagano prefecture--correspondence, 1961 July 29- December 18 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    Material in Japanese.
  - Sister-city program with Matsumoto city, Nagano prefecture--correspondence, 1963 January 1-1964 April 7 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Sister-city program with Matsumoto city, Nagano prefecture--correspondence, 1965 January 1-December 18 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Spotlight on the Orient program--correspondence, 1959 October 9-15 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    "Spotlight of the Orient"
  - Takahiko Mikami visit to Utah--correspondence, 1962 September 13-1963 July 12 (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - United Nations Model Assembly--correspondence, 1957 January 24-1957 April 24 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    3rd Annual United Nations Model Assembly.
  - Fujiwara Opera Company--Program of "Puccini's Madame Butterfly" on Good Will Tour, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper clippings--international relationships, mostly Japan related, 1951-1959 (Box 105, Folder 18)
- Japanese American Citizens League
  - Booklet and banquet program--25th Anniversary of JACL Salt Lake Chapter, 1960 October 29 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence--Activities on civil rights, 1959 May 4-1962 July 4 (Box 105, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence--Between Sahuro Kido and Henry Y. Kasai, 1935 March 4; 1935 March 19 (Box 105, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence--Regarding organizing JACL in Utah., 1935-1936 (Box 105, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence--Utah State fishing laws related, addressed to Yoshihiko Kasai, 1937 February 21-1937 April 5 (Box 105, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence--Utah State fishing laws related, written by Yoshihiko Kasai, 1937 February 6-1937 October 7 (Box 105, Folder 24)
  - Documents--Goodwill Banquet in honor of Hon. Kaju Nakamura, ca. 1938 (Box 105, Folder 25)
  - Documents--Utah State fishing laws related, 1933-1937 June 22 (Box 105, Folder 26)
  - Downtown Japanese district planning--Meeting minutes, 1964 August 12-1964 September 25 (Box 105, Folder 27)
  - Downtown Japanese district planning--Miscellaneous material, 1964 May 29-ca. 1964 August (Box 105, Folder 28)
  - Downtown Japanese district planning--Newspaper clippings, 1964 July 30-1964 August 12 (Box 105, Folder 29)
  - Downtown Japanese district planning--Questionnaire and notes, ca. 1963 (Box 105, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper clippings, ca. 1935-1941 (Box 105, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper clippings--Activities on civil rights, ca. 1959-1964 (Box 105, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper clippings--Citizenship and naturalization programs, 1959 (Box 105, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper clippings--Utah State fishing laws related, 1937 February 18-June 23 (Box 105, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper clippings--Utah State fishing laws related, 1937 February 26-March 22 (Box 105, Folder 35)
  - Passport requirements for American citizens of Japanese parentage--Citizenship and naturalization programs, ca. 1959 (Box 105, Folder 36)
  - Printed material--Activities on civil rights (federal laws), 1960 October 26-ca.1964 (Box 105, Folder 37)
    "Federal Employees Health Act of 1959", "House Bill 16: Civil Rights - Anti-Discrimination Bill."
  - Printed material--Basic Rights of Individuals, ca. 1959-1964 (Box 105, Folder 38)
  - Printed material--First Annual Intermountain Nisei Vocational Conference, 2nd Annual Utah Nisei Conference, 1934 December 27; 1938 June 10 (Box 105, Folder 39)
  - Printed material--Salt Lake County Fish and Game Association, 1937-1938 (Box 105, Folder 40)
  - Printed material--Utah Citizens Organization for Civil Rights, 1961 November 30 (Box 105, Folder 41)
    Board of directors meeting minutes and address list.
  - Script--"Hina Matsuri" radio program, 1938 March 3 (Box 105, Folder 42)
  - Typescript--Activities on civil rights, 1959 March (Box 105, Folder 43)
    Statistical reports on Japanese Americans.
  - Typescript--Brief History of the Japanese American Citizens League by Yoshihiko Kasai, ca. 1923-1948 (Box 105, Folder 44)
  - Typescript--Constitution of the Japanese American Citizens League, ca. 1923-1941 (Box 105, Folder 45)
- Japanese Association of Utah
  - Alien Land Law, 1927 (Box 105, Folder 46)
    Carbon copy of report prepared by Claude T. Baunes for the Japanese Association of Utah.
  - Articles of Incorporation of Japanese Association of Utah, 1917 August (Box 105, Folder 47)
    Carbon copy.
  - Bon Odori festival and other Japanese cultural activities--newspaper clippings, 1935 August 5-1940 March 16 (Box 105, Folder 48)
  - Bon Odori festival--correspondence and photographs, 1935 August 7-1937 August 11 (Box 105, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1926-ca. 1941 (Box 105, Folder 50)
    In Japanese and English, including receipts.
  - Correspondence and documents--Related to Mr. Kasai and the Japanese Community in Utah, 1936-1937 (Box 105, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence--Promoting better United States-Japan relations, 1933 October 8-1940 February 27 (Box 105, Folder 52)
  - House Bill 84: Anti Alien Land Law, ca. 1925 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    Carbon copy. Prepared by Claude T. Barnes, attorney for the Japanese Association of Utah.
  - K.S.L. children's hour program, 1930 May 14 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    Itinerary for radio program.
  - Lectures of Torao Kawasaki, Vice-consul, Consulate General of Japan at San Francisco, 1927 May (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous material--Good Will Friendship Dolls, 1927 April 25-1931 March 3 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondences and a newspaper clipping.
  - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings--Promoting better United States-Japan relations, 1928 January 27-1936 February 3 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Statistical reports on the Japanese population and Japanese farmers in Utah for the year 1920 to 1926 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Summer school name list, and "Bulletin #19 Proposed scope of the emergency education program in the works progress administration", 1935-1936 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Utah assembly bill regarding alien property ownership, 1927 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    Carbon copy
- Salt Lake City Nisei Victory Committee
  - Activities report, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Advisory board roster, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Constitution, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1943 August 12-1944 April 17 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1944 October 8-1944 September 28 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1944 November 3-28 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1944 December 10-30 (Box 106, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 January 1-31 (Box 106, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 February 4-26 (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 March 3-29 (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 April 2-22 (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 May 8-23 (Box 106, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 June 7-8 (Box 106, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 July 1-30 (Box 106, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 August 14-30 (Box 106, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 September 2-30 (Box 106, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 October 1-26 (Box 106, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 November 4-29 (Box 106, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1945 December 3-29 (Box 106, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1946 January 2-10 (Box 106, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1946 February 4-20 (Box 106, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1946 March 5-18 (Box 106, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1946 April 20-July 24 (Box 106, Folder 32)
    Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1946 August 6-November 17 (Box 106, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, 1947 January 5-17 (Box 106, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence--from Nisei soldiers to Alice Kasai, Chairman of the Nisei Victory Committee, ca. 1943-1947 (Box 106, Folder 35)
  - Policies of Nisei victory committee, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Roster of junior hostesses, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1944 - 1945 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    Includes newspaper clippings and photographs of the committee and Nisei soldiers.
  - Scrapbook, 1944 August 18- 1946 January 1 (Box 721, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs, newspaper clippings, flyers, and name list
  - Scrapbook, 1944 September-1946 January (Box 721, Folder 2)
    Includes announcements, correspondences from Nisei soldiers, financial statements, and newspaper clippings
- Sino-Japanese relations
  - Affidavit--Claude T. Barnes regarding Yoshihiko [Henry] Kasai, 1943 October 18 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Booklet--"Japan, Manchuria and China" by J.R. Geary, 1932 February 29 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence--J.W. Wilkens to Sterling W. Sill (Box 107, Folder 6)
    Regarding Yoshihiko [Henry] Kasai, his Sino-Japanese position, and employment at New York Life Insurance Company.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934-1938 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    English-language papers.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934-1941 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    Regarding Japan's China policy. Japanese-language papers.
  - Newspaper clippings--"The Hokubei Asahi", 1934 June 18-1935 April 29 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings--"The New World-Sun Daily", 1936 January 1 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clippings--"The Rafu Shimpo", 1935 June 23-1936 July 15 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings--Japan's China policy related, "The Japanese American News", 1935 July 1- 1936 July 20 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Notes--Regarding Japanese character, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Printed material--"ROTOGRAM" agendas of the Ogden Rotary Club, 1932 February 17 and 24 (Box 107, Folder 14)
    Regarding Henry Kasai's presentation "The Sino-Japanese Controversy"
  - Scrapbook, 1929 - 1941 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    Contains newspaper clippings and typescripts on cultural activities of the Japanese community in Salt Lake city, Nisei and US-Japan relations.
  - Typescript-- "Japanese in America", n.d. (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Typescript--"Japan and Manchuria" by J.R. Geary, 1932 January 29 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    Address to Los Angeles Rotary Club.
  - Typescript--"Quien Sabe?" by Alva Lee, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - Typescript--"Sino-Japanese Dispute in Manchuria", 1931 November 17 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    Address before the Round Table Club luncheon.
  - Typescript--"Suggestion for the Fundamental Solution of the Sino-Japanese Problems", 1932 March (Box 107, Folder 20)
    Presented to the members of the Commission of Enquiry of the League of Nations by the Japan Economic Federation
  - Typescript--"The Love of nature among the Japanese, ca. 1931 (Box 107, Folder 21)
  - Typescript--"The Manchoukuo and Sino-Japanese Problems", 1932 November 25 (Box 107, Folder 22)
    Address before the Cosmopolitan club, West High School
  - Typescript--"The Permanent Bases of Japanese Foreign Policy" by Viscount Kikujiro Ishii, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - Typescript--"The Soul of Great Harmony", n.d. (Box 107, Folder 24)
  - Typescript--Address to M.I.A. Fourteenth Ward, 1933 February 14 (Box 107, Folder 25)
- Yoshihiko Kasai
  - Business papers
    - Business and association cards of Yoshihiko Kasai, 1915-1941 (Box 108, Folder 1)
      Also includes several miscellaneous cards.
    - Business cards, A-J, 1915 - 1941 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Business cards, K-R, 1915 - 1941 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Business cards, S-Y, 1915 - 1941 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and printed material, 1915, 1919; 1933 June 1-1954 May 24 (Box 108, Folder 5)
      Includes New York Life Company brochure.
    - Financial records--Eagle Laundry Company, 1931 April-1964 February (Box 108, Folder 6)
      Includes articles of incorporation.
    - New York Life Insurance Company office records-Rolodex cards of policy holders handled by Kasai Yoshihiko, 1915-1924 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - New York Life Insurance Company office records-Rolodex cards of policy holders handled by Kasai Yoshihiko, 1925-1926 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - New York Life Insurance Company office records-Rolodex cards of policy holders handled by Kasai Yoshihiko, 1927 -1952 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - New York Life Insurance Company office records-Rolodex cards of policy holders handled by Kasai Yoshihiko, 1944; 1951-1952; 1924-1950 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - New York Life Insurance Company--correspondence, 1932 September-1947 February (Box 109, Folder 3)
      Regarding Kasai's effort to revise the discriminatory policy of the New York Life Insurance Company which was affecting his Japanese clients. Includes newspaper clipping in English and Japanese
    - New York Life Insurance Company--miscellaneous business records, 1915-1965 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      Includes a copy of Japanese family registration of Ishida family.
    - Notebooks, 1915-1941 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - New York Life Insurance Company office records-Rolodex cards of policy holders handled by Kasai Yoshihiko, ca. 1952 (Box 866, Folder 1)
      Alphabetical list of policy holders.
  - Personal papers
    - Biographical information, 1924, 1965 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Clippings--golf championship related, 1935 May-June (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Clippings--Nisei-related, 1933-1935 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Coordinating committee minutes, 1972 September 29 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--Chamber of Commerce, 1925 March 5, 1925 November 23 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence--Immigration of acquaintances, 1940, 1960-1961 (Box 109, Folder 11)
      Regarding Mitsuye Kobayashi and Takimi Yamada, whom Yoshihiko Kasai assisted. Includes newspaper clippings in Japanese
    - Correspondence--Japanese American Citizens League, 1939, 1947, 1954 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence--various incoming and outgoing, 1918, 1925-1965 (Box 109, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs.
    - Education records--Idaho Falls High School, 1909-1913, 1915 (Box 109, Folder 14)
      Grade reports and printed material.
    - Family registration in Japan, 1909 (Box 110, Folder 1)
      Copy in Japanese.
    - Financial records, 1913 December-1966 February (Box 110, Folder 2)
      Materials in English and Japanese.
    - Immigration documents, 1904, 1924, 1951 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Internment camp--camp regulations, ca. 1942 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Internment--correspondence, 1942 October 22-1945 November 19 (Box 110, Folder 5)
      Yoshihiko Kasai's internment and release
    - Internment--list of camp internees, ca. 1942 (Box 110, Folder 6)